August 10th, 2010 a. t. b.
（ナレーター）
皇暦2010年８月10日
In a blitzkrieg attack by the
Holy Empire of Britannia,
神聖ブリタニア帝国の
電撃作戦により―
日本国は
わずか１か月で征服され―
the nation of Japan was
conquered in a mere month
and its very name
was erased from the world.
世界から―
その名は消し去られた
そして―
And so, these islands
in the far east
その極東の島々は
“エリア11”と呼ばれ―
were renamed Area 11
and became an imperial province.
帝国の属州となった
（レイラ･マルカル）
革命暦228年 フロレアル18日
Revolutionary Calendar, year 228.
Floreal 18th.
The EU Army's 132nd Regiment carried out
the operation to retake St. Petersburg.
ペテルブルグ奪還のため―
作戦を決行した
我がユーロピア連合軍132連隊
However, their route was blocked
by the Britannian Army,
しかし 作戦計画を
すでに察知していた―
which had already
caught wind of the plan,
ブリタニア軍によって
進路を阻まれ―
and they were surrounded in Narva,
a city southwest of St. Petersburg.
ペテルブルグ南西の街
ナルヴァで包囲された
我がｗＺＥＲＯ(ダブルゼロ)特別攻撃隊は―
My team, Assault Unit wZERO,
launched a strike operation
against the enemy blockade
その孤立した
132連隊救出のため―
敵包囲網に対し
突撃作戦を開始した
in order to rescue
the isolated regiment.
The soldiers that comprised the unit
were youths from what was once Japan.
その攻撃隊の兵士たちは
旧日本人の少年たち
The survival rate of this operation
was painfully close to zero.
この作戦の生還率は
限りなくゼロに近い
（エリザベート）ニャー
Politicians, hoping to avoid the
public backlash that would result
（レイラ）
戦争でユーロピア連合軍兵士の
命が失われることによる―
from the loss of the lives
of EU soldiers in the war,
世論の反発を避けたい
政治家たちは―
正規の国民にカウントされない
旧日本人たちの命で―
are bolstering the army's ranks
with former Japanese,
who do not count
as official citizens.
その埋め合わせをしている
I myself am complicit in this.
私も それに加担している…
（イレヴンの少年兵）うわぁーっ！
Frame 4, signal lost.
（ヒルダ･フェイガン）
４号機 信号消失！
（クロエ･ウィンケル）
残りのアレクサンダ 11機！
Remaining Alexanders, 11!
（オリビア･ロウエル）
敵ナイトメア群
作戦エリアに進入！
Enemy Knightmare group
has entered operation area!
（ソフィ･ランドル）
パニックの症状がおさまらないわ
I can't keep their panic suppressed.
Joe Wise, try using steroids.
ジョウ･ワイズ
ステロイドを使ってみて！
I'm injecting them, but it doesn't
seem to be helping...
（ジョウ･ワイズ）
投入してるんですが…
うまくいかないな…
Most of the pilots
are close to burning out.
（フェリッリ･バルトロウ）
パイロットのほとんどが
ショートしかけてる
（ケイト･ノヴァク）でも見て！
この子だけは まだ―
But look at this. This boy seems to be
the only one who's still doing fine.
平気みたい
That's Akito...
（フェリッリ）アキトね
（日向(ひゅうが)アキト）ククククッ…
（オペレーター）
敵機群 Ｆライン突破！
Enemy force has breached F line!
Enemy frame lost!
敵機消滅！
（オペレーター）味方機も
３機同時に シグナル消滅！
Signals of three friendlies
lost at the same time!
No doubt about it...
The enemy is self-destructing!
（オペレーター）
間違いありません！
敵は自爆しています！
Don't let the enemy close in!
Destroy them before they can get close!
（騎士）敵を近づけるな！
接近する前に 撃破させろ！
Another self-destruct!
Four friendlies lost!
また自爆です！
味方機 ４機消滅！
Here come more!
（オペレーター）更に来ます！
（クロエ）８号機 自爆確認！
２機の敵ナイトメアが消滅！
Frame 8, self-destruct confirmed!
Two enemy Knightmares destroyed!
Only two?!
（ピエル･アノウ）
たった２機…！？ チッ
Don't back down! Make them advance!
Get in there and latch onto the enemy!
ひるむな！ 前進させろ！
さっさと敵を捕捉させろ！
Commander Anou.
（レイラ）アノウ司令
（アノウ）あん！？
It is now 40 minutes until the 132nd
Regiment begins their withdrawal.
132連隊の撤退開始まで
40分を切りました
I'm well aware of that,
Staff Officer Malcal!
そんなこと分かってる！
マルカル参謀！
What's going on here? Why are there
more enemy frames than you estimated?
これは どういうことか？
君の予測より敵機の数が多いのは
なぜなのだ？
Even in surprise attacks, if more
than an hour's mission time elapses,
奇襲とはいえ 作戦開始から
１時間以上 経過すれば―
作戦域を敵に特定されるのも
必然かと思われますが？
it is inevitable that the theater of
operations will be pinpointed.
Spare me your excuses! Or is it
that this plan was flawed all along?
言い訳はいい！
そもそも この作戦に
欠陥があるんじゃないのか？
It was you who made last-minute
alterations to the plan, Commander Anou.
直前に作戦計画に
修正を加えられたのは―
アノウ司令です
You don't approve of me adding
self-destruct devices to the Alexanders?
自爆システムを
アレクサンダに加えたのが不服か？
A plan that wastefully depletes
one's own forces, tactically speaking,
むやみに兵力を消耗させる作戦は
戦術としては―
...is cowardice.
邪道です
フン どうせ死ぬのは
イレヴンたちだ
It's only Elevens that are dying.
君の青臭いヒューマニズムも
イレヴンには必要ない！
The Elevens don't need
your naive humanism.
君も知っているだろう？
Come, surely you've
heard of this.
These Elevens are the descendants
of a race of people
イレヴンどもは昔から
切腹とか カミカゼとか言って―
who have always loved to die in acts
they called seppuku and kamikaze!
死ぬことが大好きな
民族の末裔だ！
What could possibly be wrong with making
them take part in a suicide operation?
そんなイレヴンどもに
自爆作戦を強いるのが なぜ悪い！
Are you sure that's wise?
本当によろしいのですか？
What are you talking about?
何のことだ？
If our forces are wiped out and
the Britannian intercept line holds,
このまま彼らが全滅し―
ブリタニア軍の迎撃ラインが
維持されれば―
as they retreat from Narva,
the 132nd Regiment will be--
ナルヴァから撤退する132連隊は…
If Operation Alpha fails, the blame
will fall on us of the wZERO unit,
α作戦が失敗すれば―
132連隊の脱出路を
確保するはずだった―
since we were supposed to secure
an escape route for them.
我らｗＺＥＲＯ部隊の
責任が問われます
Do you believe that General HQ
in Paris and the politicians
作戦失敗時に起こるであろう
市民からの糾弾を―
パリの統合本部や 政治家たちが
素直に受けるとお思いですか？
will meekly accept the public backlash
that is sure to come if the plan fails?
Statesmen never let
themselves get sullied.
為政者たちは
自らの手を汚すことはありません
こっ… こんな所で
捨て石にされてたまるか
I-I refuse to let myself be
the fall guy for this...
I still... I...
私にはまだ… 私は…
I...
私は…
This is your fault!
貴様のせいだ！
Why should... Why should I
have to take the blame
（アノウ）貴様の…―
貴様の立てた作戦のために―
for the plan that you
put together?!
この私が なぜ
責任を取らなければならない！
Leila!
（アンナ･クレマン）レイラ！
（ジョウ）はっ
怖いよ… 怖いよ
This isn't happening...
貴様が…
You're going to--
あなたには無理です
You don't have what it takes.
何？
What?
あっ は… はなせ…
L-Let go! Let go of me!
はっ はなせー！
What's going on?
Who discharged their weapon?
（オスカー･ハメル）何ごとです？
誰が発砲したのですか？
Why, if it isn't Maj. Hammel of the
Special Forces. That was certainly fast.
これは これは
特務のハメル少佐殿
お早いご登場で
（レイラ）
ひと言 訂正させて頂きます
Allow me to correct you on one detail.
They aren't "Elevens," they're Japanese.
彼らはイレヴンではなく
日本人です
Major Malcal.
（オスカー）マルカル少佐
（レイラ）んっ
Is that jiujitsu?
Most impressive.
柔術ですか？ お見事ですね
（アノウ）うっ おい！ ハメル…
Damn it, Hammel!
Maj. Hammel, get this
crazy bitch off me!
ハメル少佐 こいつを…
この女を… うっ
（オスカー）
状況説明をお願いします
マルカル少佐
Would you mind explaining what
happened here, Maj. Malcal?
Emergency Appointment #305!
Lt. Col. Claus!
緊急事例三〇五号！
クラウス中佐
Right you are...
Deputy Commander Claus
acknowledges change of command...
クラウス副司令
司令官の交代を承認… と
どうぞ マルカル司令官殿
It's all yours,
Commander Malcal.
Change in plans! Disengage all
Alexander self-destruct devices!
作戦変更 アレクサンダの
自爆ユニット解除！
クレマン大尉
Capt. Clement!
Y-Yes, ma'am!
あ… はい！
Chloe! Hilda! Send emergency
texts to all frames!
クロエ！ ヒルダ！
各機に緊急メールを！
Looks like our boss
is feeling her oats.
うちのボス 元気出てきたね
Good for her.
よかった～
Surrounded, huh?
囲まれたか
Disengage bomb?
爆装解除？
Lord Wilhelm, we've lost the
signal from Third Platoon!
（オペレーター）ヴェルヘルム様
第３小隊の信号が消滅しました
The Ghost of Hannibal, eh?
（ヴェルヘルム）
ハンニバルの亡霊か… あっ
Is that it?
あれか！
ナイトメア！
A Knightmare?
Die!
死ね！
Damn monster!
バケモノが！
（オペレーター）
ヴェルヘルム隊 全滅！
シグナルが消えました
Wilhelm Squad annihilated.
Signal has been lost!
Sir Farnese, please
request reinforcements.
（参謀）ファルネーゼ卿
援軍の要請をお出し下さい
I believe that our forces alone
are no longer able to hold the line.
もはや 我が軍団だけでは
支えきれないかと…
Without knowing the
full measure of the enemy,
（アンドレア･ファルネーゼ）
敵の全容も定かではないまま―
このエリアに 味方を
引き入れることはできない
I cannot draw more of our forces
into this area.
死ね！
Die!
（オーギュスト）何！
What?!
DIE!
（アキト）死ね！！
おのれ！
Damn you!
I don't believe in ghosts!
私は亡霊など信じぬ！
Removal of enemy Knightmare squads
from combat zone complete.
（サラ･デインズ）作戦域から
敵ナイトメア部隊の排除完了
132nd Regiment
has begun evacuation.
（オリビア）
132連隊 撤退を開始しました
Remaining troop strength
of attack unit?
攻撃部隊の残存兵力は？
Currently verifying.
今 確認中です
あ １機！
One frame! Receiving pilot
biometrics, as well!
パイロットの生命反応もあります
ヒュウガ少尉…
2nd Lt. Hyuga...
It's 2nd Lt. Akito Hyuga!
ヒュウガ･アキト少尉です！
Remaining forces, rendezvous with G1
in 13th area! Withdraw from combat area!
（騎士）
残存部隊は13エリアで Ｇ１と合流
戦闘域から離脱！
Activate main engine!
（オペレーター）
メインエンジン始動
#2 combat speed!
我ら 聖ラファエル騎士団が―
To think that knights of the
Holy Order of Raphael
could not hold our own
against Europian militia soldiers...
ユーロピアの市民兵の軍相手に―
持ちこたえられなかったとは
Sir Farnese.
（参謀）ファルネーゼ卿…
（ファルネーゼ）
戦いに倒れた者たちの弔いは―
We must give proper burials
to our brothers who fell in battle.
丁重に行わなければな
（ＥＵ軍兵士）やっと帰れるぜ
We can finally go home!
ったく 援軍が来るのが
おせーんだよな
I swear, it took those reinforcements
long enough to get here!
I didn't mind. Just think
of it as camping out.
（ＥＵ軍兵士）でも いいんじゃね
キャンプしてたと思えば
（ＥＵ軍兵士）
ああ それ言えてるな
Yeah, you could say that.
（ＥＵ軍兵士）
戦争なんて ちょろいもんだぜ
War's a piece of cake!
What are you doing?
You by yourself?
（ＥＵ軍兵士）
何やってんだ？ お前一人か？
Yes. Can you give us a lift?
ああ あれも乗せてくれないか
（ＥＵ軍兵士）あ？
ナイトメア？ 見かけない型だな
That Knightmare? I've never
seen that model before.
Just to be safe,
show me your ID.
念のためだ ＩＤ見せろよ
こんな所まで 大変だったな…
You're a long way from home,
that's for sure.
チッ イレヴンかよっ
A damn Eleven?
I'll give you a lift, but only if you
ride in back with the Knightmare.
あのナイトメアと一緒に―
後ろの荷台になら
乗っけてやるよ
（レイラ）生還者１名
One survivor.
私の作戦は―
My plan was a success, but at the cost
of the lives of many Japanese youths.
旧日本人の若者たちの
命と引き換えに 成功した
My father told me that it was the duty
of a citizen to protect his homeland.
祖国を守ることは
人民の義務であると父は言った
But do the citizens
of this republic--
だが この共和国の市民たちは…
Do I appear to be a cowardly commander,
hiding safe in her castle
私もまた―
城に隠れる臆病な指揮官に
見えているのだろうか―
to these people who have
lost their homeland?
祖国をなくした彼らには…
（ジィーン･スマイラス）
レイラ･マルカル少佐を中佐に昇進
Major Leila Malcal is hereby promoted
to the rank of Lt. Colonel.
She is officially installed as the
commander of Assault Unit wZERO.
正式にｗＺＥＲＯ部隊の
司令官に任命する
昨日 国防40人委員会で了承した
The 40 Man Defense Committee
approved it yesterday.
In recognition of the success of the
Narva evacuation plan, I assume.
ナルヴァ撤退作戦 成功の功だな
Congratulations, Leila.
おめでとう レイラ
Leila Malcal gratefully
accepts her new duties.
（レイラ）
レイラ･マルカル 拝命致します
（スマイラス）
私は君に期待しているのだよ
I expect great things
from you.
The wZERO unit was based
on your proposal.
ｗＺＥＲＯ部隊は
君の発案によるものだ
司令官は君こそ ふさわしい
It's only fitting that you
should be its commander.
What's the matter? You don't
seem very happy about it.
どうした？
あまり うれしそうではないな
スマイラス将軍
General Smilas, the intent
of my Attack Plan 145A
私の“145Ａ攻撃計画”の
主意は―
ナイトメア部隊で 敵陣背後を
奇襲攻撃することです
is to launch sneak attacks on the rear flanks
of enemy positions using Knightmare forces.
For that reason, this plan requires the
commitment of a large number of troops.
故に この作戦には
戦力の大量投入が必要なのです
If it continues to be carried out
using small forces as it was this time,
ですが 今回のような
小部隊での作戦実行では―
the losses incurred by wZERO
will be untenable.
我が方の兵力の消耗が
激しすぎます
Please let me expand the unit
using Europian Army regular forces.
ユーロピア軍正規兵による
部隊の拡充を…
I understand your idealism, but sending
regular forces isn't so simple, Leila.
理想は分かるが―
正規軍の投入は
簡単ではないのだよ レイラ
Public opinion is against the idea
of Republic soldiers dying in this war.
世論は戦争で共和国の兵士が
死ぬことを よしとはしない
Analysis by the Joint Chiefs of Staff
determined that the survival rate
145Ａ攻撃計画は―
“兵士たちの生還率が低い”との
参謀本部調査室の分析もある
of soldiers in Attack Plan 145A
would be low.
Are you saying that you're fine with
people dying as long as they're Elevens, sir?
イレヴンなら いくら死んでも
かまわないとおっしゃるのですか！
（スマイラス）レイラ
Leila, only a fool tries to make sense
of every little thing.
物事の全てを
明確にしようとするのは―
愚鈍な者どもの思考だ
（レイラ）しかし…
But, sir!
（スマイラス）正論だけで
人は納得させられないのだよ
It takes more than sound arguments
to win people over.
先日のナルヴァ作戦で―
In the Narva operation
the other day,
the number of Japanese soldiers
who managed to come home alive
帰還できた日本人の兵は―
was exactly one.
たった一人でした
You saved the lives of
15,000 Europian soldiers.
君は１万5,000もの
ユーロピアの兵を救ったのだ
（レイラ）私は…
I didn't--
However, you really ought to show
some regret over the incident
（スマイラス）だが
作戦中での アノウ中佐の件は―
反省してもらわないといけないな
with Lt. Col. Anou
during the operation.
（レイラ）反省はしています…
I do regret it. I should have removed him
before the operation began.
作戦前に
排除しておくべきでした
Typical...
まったく…
Anou has been reassigned
to the Warsaw supply force.
アノウ中佐はワルシャワの
補給部隊に転属となった
It would seem that HQ has finally
realized where his aptitudes lie, too.
司令部も やっと
彼の適正に気付いたようだな
There will be another meeting of
the 40 Man Committee tomorrow.
明日も40人委員会の会議がある
Another one, sir?
明日もですか？
Incompetent politicians and bureaucrats
find comfort in meetings.
無能な政治家や官僚は
会議をすることで安心する
It might do you some good
to sit in on one as an observer.
君も一度
見学しておくのがよいだろう
Yes, sir.
はい
That reminds me, Leila.
Do you have any plans for later?
（スマイラス）そういえば レイラ
君の このあとの予定は？
I'm attending a party to celebrate the
troops' return from the Narva operation.
ナルヴァ作戦
帰還祝賀パーティーに出席します
お待たせしました ヒュウガ中尉
I'm sorry I kept you,
Lt. Hyuga.
There's no need
to be apologetic.
（アキト）気遣いは無用です
My current assignment
is to be your guard.
マルカル司令の警護が
今の任務ですから
Fine, fine...
Right you are.
（レイラ）はいはい そうですね
パリは初めてですか 中尉？
Is this your first time
in Paris, Lieutenant?
（アキト）昔 来たことがあります
I came here once, long ago.
That painting fetched
a rather tidy sum.
（男性）
あの絵は いい値が付きましたよ
（男性）今の投機は
金より そちらのほうが…
It's better to speculate in art
these days, not gold.
Nonsense, investing in national bonds
in wartime is much more lucrative.
（男性）いやいや 戦時国債も
投資としては有望ですよ
（男性）ブリタニアは まだ戦争を
拡大する気はないみたいですしね
True, Britannia doesn't appear to have
any interest in expanding the war.
It's best when both sides are simply
glaring at each other like they are now.
（男性）
今みたいに 睨み合っているだけが
一番いいのですよ
I suppose a war without fighting
is much more profitable than peace.
（男性）戦わない戦争が
平和より金になるって訳ですな
Perhaps I should have invested more...
（男性）
もっと投資したほうが
よいですかね
We have non-alcoholic fruit juice, sir.
（女性）ノンアルコールは
フレッシュジュースがありますが
You bankers are terrible...
（男性）
銀行屋は悪どいですな
That's fine.
（アキト）それでいいよ
Look at her... Can you believe she's
wearing a military uniform here?
（女性）ほら あの人…
ここに軍服なんてね…
（女性）ああ マルカル家の…
Ah, she's that Malcal girl.
（男性）ああ 例のお嬢様…
Oh, the young lady
we've heard so much about.
I see that no one comes over
to speak to a woman
（アキト）パーティー会場で―
ギベールの「戦術一般論」を
読んでる女性には―
who is reading Guibert's
A General Essay on Tactics at a party.
誰も近づいてきませんね
ヒュウガ中尉にも―
Why, Lt. Hyuga, you do
have a sense of humor.
ユーモアのセンスが
あったのですね
This is my first time inside
the Palais des Tuileries,
パリのチュイルリー宮殿に
来たのは初めてですが―
さすが―
but this definitely lives up to my image
of a Bien Natio conglomerate party.
ビアン･ナシオ･コンツェルン
主催のパーティーですね
ナルヴァ作戦の
成功を祝してでしたか？
Wasn't this to celebrate the success
of the Narva operation?
何の祝賀パーティーだか…
I have no idea
what they're celebrating.
We're the only
two soldiers here.
軍人なんて
私たち以外 誰もいない
Leila!
（ダニエル･マルカル）レイラ！
Leila Malcal!
レイラ･マルカル！
Ah, excuse me. Begging your pardon.
おー ちょっと失礼
ちょっと すみません
（ステファン･マルカル）
すみません
Sorry. Our apologies.
Why didn't you call to say that you would be coming, Leila?
（ダニエル）来てるのなら
なぜ連絡をしてくれないんだ
レイラ
（ステファン）
１年ぶりなんだよ 君に会うのも…
It's been a whole year
since we last saw you.
It's been too long, Daniel. Stefan.
（レイラ）お久しぶりです
ダニエルお兄様 ステファンお兄様
Leila, why in the world are you
wearing that to a perfectly good party?
レイラ せっかくのパーティーに
その格好は どういうことだ
Please stop this boorish nonsense.
あまり不粋なマネは よしなさい
A military uniform is formal wear for me.
軍服は私の正装です
I certainly see that your tone
is the same as ever, Leila.
その口調も
相変わらずだね レイラ
As I live and breathe!
（ヨアン･マルカル）
これは これは―
If it isn't our enchanting
little sister.
麗しの妹君じゃないか
loan... Brother.
ヨアン… お兄様…
Ah, now I understand.
This is the lieutenant Eleven?
（ヨアン）ほおー なるほどね
イレヴンの中尉殿か
This is Lt. Hyuga, my bodyguard.
警護のヒュウガ中尉です
Pleased to meet you.
（アキト）はじめまして
（ヨアン）僕もレイラの兄貴でね
I'm another one of Leila's
big brothers.
loan Malcal,
the third Malcal boy.
マルカル家の三男
ヨアン･マルカルだ
It's a pleasure to make
your acquaintance, Lieutenant.
お見知りおきを 中尉
Oh, right. Perhaps I should
get this out of the way.
そうだ…
これも
言っておいたほうがいいかな？
She also happens
to be my fiancée.
彼女はさ
僕の婚約者(フィアンセ)でもあるんだよ
こいつはさ―
This young lady was adopted
into the Malcal family.
うちの…
マルカル家の養女なんだよ
でも 親父の大のお気に入りでね
But she also happens to be
the apple of our father's eye.
So he went and decided that
we should be married.
だから俺との結婚も
親父の決めたことさ
loan!
ヨアン！
（ヨアン）ふんっ
（レイラ）う… あっ
But the thing is, I have absolutely no
interest in marrying the likes of you.
でもな…―
俺はお前なんかと
結婚する気は ないんだよ
Stop this nonsense, loan.
（ダニエル）やめなさい ヨアン…
（ステファン）
いいかげんにしないか！
Behave yourself!
Oh, I know! I'll make you my mistress!
You'll be my kept woman!
そうだ お前は 妾(めかけ)にしてやろう！
俺の妾だ！
お前には
それがお似合いだ レイラ
That's what would
suit you best, Leila!
ああ すみません
Oh, my apologies.
きっ… 貴様！
Why, you little--
Did you know that all Elevens
are masters of bladed weapons?
イレヴンは皆 刃物の使い手なのを
ご存じですか？
お望みなら ここで―
If you like, I'll be happy to carve your
face to ribbons right here and now.
あなたの顔を
切り刻んでみせましょう
はっ はなせ！
Let go! Please, let go of me!
はなしてくれー！
（アキト）どうぞ
Here.
Please use this.
これをお使い下さい
Shall we go, Commander Malcal?
行きましょう マルカル司令
Lt. Hyuga?
（レイラ）ヒュウガ中尉…
Hey! Wait!
ちょっと 待って下さい！
（レイラ）剣術が得意だとは
知りませんでした
I had no idea that you were a
swordplay specialist, Lieutenant.
What do you mean?
（アキト）何のことですか？
Back there, you said you were
a master of bladed weapons.
（レイラ）
さっき 刃物の使い手って…
Ah, that.
You Europians are all the same.
ユーロピアの人たちは
皆 同じです
日本人のことを
空手家か剣術家だと思い―
You all think we're karate masters
or master swordsmen.
You fear us for no reason,
or you mock us.
異常に恐れたり あざ笑ったり…
Not me.
私は違います！
Speaking of which, I heard that you
are ranked in aikido, Commander.
そういえば マルカル司令は
合気道の有段者だそうですね
Who did you hear that from?
誰から聞いたのですか？
Capt. Clement told me.
クレマン大尉が教えてくれました
あ… おしゃべりなのは
アンナの悪いクセです
Anna needs to do something about
that gossip habit of hers.
Is it true that you and the Captain
were classmates?
クレマン大尉とは
同級生だったとか
子どもの頃です
When we were children. After I was
adopted into the Malcal family.
マルカル家の養女になってから
私の本当の両親は―
Apparently, my birth parents
were Britannian aristocrats.
ブリタニアの貴族だったそうです
Britannian?
They defected to Europia?
（アキト）ブリタニア？
ユーロピアに亡命を？
Yes. I was born here in Europia.
私はユーロピアで生まれました
But my parents died 12 years ago,
leaving me to fend for myself.
でも12年前 両親は亡くなり―
私は一人…
The Malcals, a huge conglomerate,
took me in as an orphan
巨大コンツェルンの
マルカル家は―
貴族という
血統のしるし欲しさに―
because they wanted
a claim to noble lineage.
孤児になった私を
引き取ったのです
Intending to eventually marry me
off to loan, their youngest son.
いずれは 末の息子ヨアンと
結婚させるつもりで…
Which is how he's both your
brother and your fiancé...
だから兄で… フィアンセ…
おめでたい人たちだ―
I love you people.
Always trying to see who has
the best bloodline and fortune...
血統や財産を比べ合うなんて…
ヒュウガ中尉
Lt. Hyuga.
But if you don't like it, Commander,
でも司令が嫌なのなら―
I'd be happy to
get rid of it for you...
私が消してあげましょうか？―
その世界を…
This world of yours.
85 of my crew are dead, and another
37 are in the hospital ICU.
（Ｄｒ.）
うちの若いのが85人 死に―
37人がいまだ
病院のＩＣＵにいる
And 20 of your own
have set out for Heaven.
お前たちの仲間も20人
天国へ旅立った…
Get your facts straight.
It was 18.
（佐山(さやま)リョウ）18人だ 間違うな
This is the first time a war this scale
has been fought in the Underground.
（Ｄｒ.）アンダーグラウンドで
これほど大きな戦争は―
初めてだ
リョウ･サヤマ
Ryo Sayama. We've both
paid a steep price.
お互い 多くの犠牲を払った
Let's put an end to this.
もう終わりにしよう だからだ―
With that in mind, I've prepared
a gift for you and your buddies.
お前たちへの贈り物も用意した
Ryo! I'm done
rewriting the pilot ID!
（成瀬(なるせ)ユキヤ）
リョウ パイロットＩＤの
書き換え 終わったよ
That's a good boy, Yukiya.
いい子だ ユキヤ
（Ｄｒ.）今 口座に入金があった
There was a deposit
in my bank account just now.
Was there, now?
そうかい
じゃあ 金払った訳だから―
Well, since we've paid for it, I suppose
this isn't a present from you anymore.
こいつは アンタからの
プレゼントじゃねえな
ネットバンクから
巻き上げた金で―
Don't talk so big about paying with
money you skimmed from net banks.
偉そうなこと言うんじゃない
You bunch of two-bit thieves.
コソ泥どもが…
Why don't you do it, too, then?
Assuming you can, that is.
じゃあ アンタたちも
やればいいんじゃない？―
できればの話だけど
（手下）イレヴン風情が
調子づきやがって！
Watch your mouth,
you piece of Eleven trash!
オイオイ そう熱くなるな
Come on, now. Let's not get so
hot under the collar, all right?
Ryo Sayama, you and your crew
need to show respect to your elders.
リョウ･サヤマ
お前たち若者も―
年長者に対する
敬意は払わないといけないな
ケッ 悪党がよく言うぜ
Big talk, coming from a thug.
Right, Yukiya?
なあ ユキヤ！
Let him have his fun. After all,
old folks love to lecture kids, right?
いいんじゃない
年寄りは
説教したがるものなんだよね
（香坂(こうさか)アヤノ）リョウ
マリコやシンジたちのかたきを…
Ryo. We have to avenge Mariko,
Shinji, and the rest.
Take it easy, Ayano.
焦るな アヤノ…
15… 14… 13…
15, 14, 13...
How about it, Ryo? Why don't
you join our organization?
どうだ リョウ
俺たちの組織に入らないか？
I value your talents.
お前の才能を
買っているんだよ 俺は
Thanks, but I'll pass. The thought
of being your flunky makes me puke.
遠慮しとくよ
アンタの手下なんか―
ヘドが出る
なんだと！？
What did you say?
４… ３… リョウ！
4, 3... Ryo!
うわー バラバラになってるよ
Wow, everybody's blown
to pieces...
Man, what a mess. It's gonna
be a bitch to clean this up.
（リョウ）ひでぇーな これ
掃除が大変だな
Yukiya, we won't be able to
use this ploy next time.
ユキヤ！ こいつは
次のには使えないぞ
I know.
（ユキヤ）分かってるよ
Humans sure are fragile.
人間て もろいよね
S-Somebody... I need a doctor...
Call a doctor...
（Ｄｒ.）だ… 誰か…
い… 医者を 医者を…
呼んでくれ…
（リョウ）なんだ まだ生きてたか
Well, I'll be.
Still alive, huh?
Help me...
助けてくれ…
（リョウ）
助けてやってもいいけど…
Sure, I can help you.
But what's it worth to you?
いくら払う？
自分の命は
いくらだって聞いてんだよ
Come on, I'm asking you
how much your life is worth.
クッ フッハハハ… ハハハ…
（Ｄｒ.）
お前ら テロリストの仲間か？
Are you people
with those terrorists?
（Ｄｒ.）イレヴンには
黒の騎士団とかいう…
That group you Elevens have...
The Black Knights.
Nope.
（リョウ）ちげぇーよ
What we're after...
俺たちの望みは―
世界の平和
...is world peace.
Yukiya, Ayano.
Next time, it's the real deal.
ユキヤ アヤノ
本番は これからだ
I know, I know.
（ユキヤ）分かってるさ
フフフ… 楽しくなるね これから
Things are about to get fun!
（スマイラス）
我がユーロピア連合共和国は―
Ever since the revolution
300 years ago,
the United Republic of Europia
has maintained its republic system.
300年前の革命以来
共和制を維持している
が 今この共和国を覆う
無責任主義―
However, what the revolution
might really have given rise to
利己主義の果ての拝金主義は―
is the money-worship
that has overrun this republic
that is the end result
of irresponsibility and self-interest.
その革命が
もたらしたのかもしれないのだよ
That's even true for those who
claim to be this country's leaders.
この国のリーダーを
標榜する者たちさえもが そうだ
このままでは ブリタニア帝国に
征服される日も近いかもしれない
If this keeps up, the day we're
conquered by Britannia might be near.
革命によって
この地から追われ―
By the descendants of the royals and nobles
who were driven from this country
新大陸に逃げた王侯貴族たちの
末裔に我々は…
and fled to the new world
because of the revolution.
だから 私は思うのだよ―
That is why I think this way:
"If only Gen. Napoleon Bonaparte,
the hero of the revolution,
革命戦争の英雄
ナポレオン･ボナパルト将軍が―
"had become emperor of all Europe
rather than dying at the guillotine..."
断頭台で処刑されず―
この大ヨーロッパの
皇帝になっていたらと…
But Napoleon tried to set
himself up as dictator.
ナポレオン将軍は独裁を…
The dictatorship of one talented man
is more beneficial to humanity
愚民どもの民主主義より―
有能なる者の独裁のほうが
人類にとって有益だ
than the democracy of
the ignorant masses.
That's what your late father
wished for, as well.
君の父上も それを望んでいた
だから殺された…
That's why he was murdered.
父が亡くなった時は
まだ小さかったので 私には…
I was still very young when Father
passed away, so I don't--
Oh, no,
I'm not criticizing him.
ああ いや―
彼を批判しているのでは
ないのだよ
Your father and I were
best friends, after all.
君の父上と私は
親友だったのだからね
The fact that we keep the Elevens
who live in Europia locked away
ブリタニアを恐れるあまり―
ユーロピアに住むイレヴンを―
in internment camps like this
out of fear of Britannia
このように
隔離収容してしまったのも―
is also cowardice resulting
from republicanism.
共和制が生んだ臆病さ故だ
Though I have little enough pity
for the Elevens for not resisting...
抵抗しないイレヴンも
情けないがな
Look at all those scrappy Eleven
grandpas and grannies out there!
（ＥＵ軍兵士）イレヴンの
ジジババは 元気だよな
I wish I could show them
to the Eleven we've got in the back!
（ＥＵ軍兵士）
後ろのイレヴンにも
見せてやりたいぜ
（ユキヤ）
標的が進入した 予定通りだ
Target has entered area.
Right on time.
警備の規模も予測通りだな
Looks like the extent of his security
is as predicted, too.
All right, let's
get this game started!
さあ ゲームを始めようか
T-minus 5 minutes.
５分前…
Is the drive beacon
coming in clearly?
（ＥＵ軍兵士）
ドライブビーコンはクリアか？
Yeah, I'm positive. This is the route
the nav system is showing.
（ＥＵ軍兵士）ああ 間違いない
ナビは このコースを示している
チッ ハッチが開かないか
The hatch is jammed, huh?
それじゃあ 行くか！
All right, let's get to it!
（ＥＵ軍兵士）早く出せ 早く！
Deploy! Hurry!
Gardmare #3,
prepare to intercept!
（ＥＵ軍兵士）
ガルドメア３号機 迎撃用意！
ザコどもが！
Stupid cannon fodder!
A Knightmare!
（レイラ）ナイトメア…
Terrorists?
テロリストか？
（レイラ）恐らく
Probably. We should stay put
for the time being.
しばらくは ここを…
General, get out!
Hurry!
将軍 早く外へ！ 早く！
Get clear, hurry!
避難しろ 早く！
Lt. Colonel, no! It's too dangerous!
Come back!
（ＥＵ軍兵士）
ダメです中佐！ 危険です！
中佐 お戻り下さい！
Shall I see how sharp
my blade is?
切れ味 試してみるか？
アヤノがターゲットを確保したよ
Ayano has secured the target.
Good. We're out of here!
（リョウ）よし 撤収するぞ
Okay!
（ユキヤ）ＯＫ
Ayano!
（リョウ）アヤノ
Take the geezer
and meet up with Yukiya!
じじいを連れて
ユキヤと合流しろ
まだいるのか？ うぜーなっ！
There was another?
What a pain in the ass...
さっさと消えな！
That's about enough from you!
（リョウ）なんだ あいつ？
Who the hell is this guy? He's trying
to go toe-to-toe with a Knightmare?
生身でナイトメアに…
He's even crazier
than we are...
俺たちより いかれてるぜ
If you're that eager to die,
そんなに死にたいなら―
I'll be happy to oblige!
殺してやるよ！
しまった！
Damn!
やべぇ
This is bad!
Crap!
くっそー
リョウ！
Ryo!
（レイラ）ヒュウガ中尉！
Lt. Hyuga!
I want you to take them alive.
彼らには生きてもらいます
Ryo!
（アヤノ）リョウー！
（レイラ）はっ
Pilot of that Glasgow!
グラスゴーのパイロット！
Your friend is my prisoner!
あなたの仲間を確保しました
Resistance is useless.
Come out of there at once!
抵抗はムダです
すぐに出てきなさい！
（リョウ）
アヤノに危害は加えるなよ！
Don't hurt Ayano!
I'm coming out!
今から出る
よっこらせっと…
Oopsie-daisy...
は？ オイオイ なんだよ
Hey, what the hell?
You're just a kid.
ガキじゃねえかよ
I don't think you're
all that far apart in age.
（レイラ）年齢は あなたと
そんなに違いはないと思います
マルカル司令
Commander Malcal.
Letting them live would
only put us at risk.
彼らは生かしておいても
危険なだけです
ヘッ 分かってるじゃねえか
I'm glad you can see that!
（アヤノ）
フッフフ その通りさ
He's right.
Let them go!
（ユキヤ）２人を はなせ！
早く！ 時間稼ぎはムダだよ
Do it now! Don't try to stall
to buy yourselves time!
２人を はなさなきゃ
これを―
Let them go right now,
or I detonate these charges.
爆破する
I dare you.
Your friends will die, too.
やってみろ 仲間も死ぬ
僕がそんな脅しでやめる
甘ちゃんに見える？
Do I look like I'd back down
over a threat like that?
Yes, you do.
見えるね
Yukiya, do it! We'll be killed if they
capture us, so you might as well!
ユキヤ 押せ！
このまま捕まって
殺されるぐらいなら―
いっそここで！
What are your demands?
要求を聞きましょう
You did all this to kidnap Gen. Smilas,
so what demands were you going to issue?
スマイラス将軍を誘拐してまでの
あなたたちの要求とは何だったの？
I wanted top-of-the-line Knightmares.
最新鋭のナイトメアが
欲しかったんだよ
ナイトメアを？
Knightmares?
Do you think you can get away
after doing something like this?
これだけのことをして
逃げきれると思うの？
We'll keep running
as long as we can.
逃げられるところまで
逃げてみるさ
今度は簡単には やられない
You can't kill us like dogs
this time.
甘いな
Don't be naive. The army will do whatever it takes
to kill you, even attacking from the air.
軍は たとえ空爆してでも―
お前たちを殺す
Please, tell me. What were you
and your people really after?
（レイラ）教えて下さい
あなたたちの本当の望みは
何だったのですか？
We want a place to belong.
（リョウ）居場所が欲しいのさ
To belong?
居場所？
お前らは バカでいいよな
I wish I was as dumb
as you people.
こんな腐った世界を作って
それで満足してんだからさ
You make a rotten world like this,
and you're perfectly content with it.
But for us Elevens, we don't belong
anywhere in this world of yours.
でも 俺たちイレヴンには―
この世界のどこにも
居場所なんてない
If you want a place for Elevens, are you
going to found a country or something?
イレヴンの居場所が
欲しいのなら―
国でも造るのか？
ほかのイレヴン全てをしょい込む
つもりなんて気は さらさらねえよ
I never had any intention
of speaking for all Elevens here.
俺たちは…―
All we want is a place
for ourselves.
俺たちだけの居場所が―
Just for us.
欲しいだけさ
If you want a place where you
can belong, I'll give you one.
あなたたちの居場所なら
私が用意します
Join my team.
That's where you can belong.
私の部隊に入ってもらいます
そこが あなたたちの居場所です
I see...
なるほどね
If we don't...
さもなきゃ…
...we get bombed, huh?
空爆か
We don't have any choice
in the matter, do we?
俺たちに―
選択肢はねえって訳か
Duke Velaines has ordered the Order of
Michael to relocate to St. Petersburg.
（ミケーレ･マンフレディ）
我らミカエル騎士団は―
ペテルブルグに移動せよと
ヴェランス大公からのご命令だ
St. Petersburg?
（シン･ヒュウガ･シャイング）
ペテルブルグ…
The Order of Raphael was destroyed in a
battle at Narva, west of St. Petersburg.
（マンフレディ）
ペテルブルグの西方
ナルヴァでの戦いで―
ラファエル騎士団が壊滅した
The enemy was a Knightmare squad
that appeared behind our lines.
敵は陣後方に出現した
ナイトメア部隊
The EU forces that struck out beyond
the western front and occupied Narva
西部戦線から突出
ナルヴァを占拠した
ユーロピア連合共和国軍は―
by all rights should have been
completely surrounded.
完全包囲していたはず
It's unlikely that reinforcements could
have easily crossed the western lines.
援軍が簡単に西部戦線を
越えられるとは思えませんが…
The enemy appeared without warning
amidst the siege line.
（マンフレディ）
敵は包囲陣の中に突如出現した
Without warning?
（シン）突如？
That is what the survivors say.
（マンフレディ）
生き残った者たちは
そう言っている
突然 どこからともなく現れたと…
They appeared suddenly,
as if out of thin air.
Just like General Hannibal
attacking the ancient Roman empire.
古代ローマ帝国を襲った
ハンニバル将軍ですね
Hannibal?
ハンニバル…
Ah, I see your point.
The "Ghost of Hannibal," indeed.
そうだな まさに
“ハンニバルの亡霊”だ
But if there are any ghosts here,
it is the Europian Union itself.
しかし亡霊と言うなら
ユーロピア連合がそれだ
The ghost of the revolution
300 years past!
やつらは300年前の革命の亡霊
己の利益しか目に映らぬ
愚民の集まりにすぎん
They're a bunch of fools who value
nothing but their own interests.
The noble-minded Euro Britannia
must oust such statesmen
その愚かしい為政者を追放し―
高潔なる我らユーロ･ブリタニアが
導かねばならない
and lead the country
in their place.
Our cause is just!
大義は我らにあり！
シン お前には東洋の
武人(もののふ)の血が流れている
Shin, the blood of Oriental warriors
flows in your veins.
You will soon be part of our legitimate
aristocracy and its thousand-year history.
我ら1000年の歴史を持つ
正統なる貴族団に加わる日も近い
（シン）ありがたき お言葉です
マンフレディ卿
Your words honor me,
Sir Manfredi.
ならば―
If that is the case, I would like you
to give me the Order of Michael.
ミカエル騎士団をいただきたい
Shin, such a brazen joke
from someone so stiff!
シン 堅物のお前にしては
過ぎた冗談だ
In five more years, you will lead the
Order of Michael as my successor.
あと５年もたてば
私の後継者として―
このミカエル騎士団を
率いることとなる
その日を私は
楽しみにしているのだ シン
How I look forward
to that day, Shin.
You mean more to me
than my own brother.
私はお前を 血を分けた
兄弟以上に思っている
Brother?
兄弟？
（マンフレディ）
そうだ 共に新しき世界へ歩もう
That's right. Let's walk
into the new world together.
（シン）最悪だ
You're horrible.
シン？
Shin?
It's unfortunate, Sir Manfredi.
（シン）残念です マンフレディ卿
You don't have what it takes
to command the Order of Michael.
あなたはミカエル騎士団
総帥の器ではない
What are you saying, Shin?
何を言う シン！
It is I...
who am better suited.
私こそが―
ふさわしい
マンフレディ卿
Sir Manfredi... It is time
to set out on your journey.
旅立ちの時です
Yes, so it is.
（マンフレディ）ああ そうだな
I will go on ahead,
Shin Hyuga Shaing.
先に行く
シン･ヒュウガ･シャイング
Goodbye, Manfredi.
さようなら マンフレディ
アキト…
Akito?
おはようございます
マルカル司令
Good morning, Comm. Malcal.
Good morning, Lt. Hyuga.
おはようございます
ヒュウガ中尉
ここで何をしているのですか？
What are you doing out here?
Keeping a promise.
（アキト）約束をしてたんですよ
A promise?
（レイラ）約束？
It's a grave for those who died
in the Narva operation.
ナルヴァ作戦で
死んでいったやつらの墓です
A grave... for those who...
ナルヴァ作戦…
彼らの…
We made a pact before the mission.
（アキト）
出撃前に約束してたんです―
The survivors would build a grave here
for those who didn't make it.
生き残った者が―
戦いで死んだ者たちの墓を ここに
I was the only survivor.
俺だけが生き残った
I'm partially to blame that they
didn't make it home alive.
彼らが生きて帰れなかったのは
私の責任でもあります
They set out on the mission
with smiles on their faces.
あいつらは
笑顔で出撃していきました
That's right.
（イレヴンの少年兵）
そうさ 俺たちは…
Because we died in battle, our families
now have full rights as EU citizens.
俺たちが戦死したから―
家族はユーロピアの
市民権を手に入れた
That's enough for us.
それで十分さ
More importantly, Akito,
why do you fight?
それよりアキト…
お前は なぜ闘っている？
You don't have a family
to protect.
（イレヴンの少年兵）
守るべき家族もいない
You don't have a country
to protect.
（イレヴンの少年兵）
守るべき国もない
You're all alone.
たった一人で…
（イレヴンの少年兵）
何のために生きている？
What do you live for?
So that I can die.
死ぬためだ
Lt. Hyuga?
（レイラ）ヒュウガ中尉
Did I say something wrong?
何か気に障りましたか？
（アキト）え？
You got quiet all of a sudden.
急に黙り込んで…
（アキト）ああ 違うんです
No, it's not that. I was talking
with them, that's all.
彼らと話をしていただけです
彼ら？
With who?
（アキト）死んだはずなのに
俺には聞こえるんですよ―
They're supposed to be dead,
but I can still hear them.
I can hear their voices.
あいつらの声が
I died myself, once.
俺は一度―
死んだんです
Soko ni iru kimi wa
The "you" standing there
ima dake no kimi ja nai.
is more than the "you" of right now.
Kyou made no yorokobi ya
You are living with all the joy
kanashimi to issho ni ikiteru.
and sadness you have ever experienced.
Ichiban taisetsu na koto wa
The most important things
Episode 1
The Wyvern Arrives
kesshite iwanakute ii
never have to be said aloud.
Kono sora ya yureru haoto ya
The sky above, the rustling leaves,
sekai ga zenbu shitteru.
and the world already know everything.
Jiyuu tte setsunaku nai desu ka?
Isn't it a painful thing to be free?
Otona ni nattan da ne.
You've grown up, haven't you?
Jiyuu tte setsunaku nai desu ka?
Isn't it a painful thing to be free?
Sukoshi dake.
Just a little.
Namida mo fukeru kurai ni
Even though I was always close enough
itsudemo chikaku ni ita hazu nano ni,
to wipe away your tears,
watashi wa kimi no kurushimi ya furue ni
I failed to notice
nani hitotsu kidzuke nakatta.
any of your pain or suffering.
Hontou ni taisetsu na mono wa
The things that are truly precious
chiisa na honou no you ni hakanai.
are as ephemeral as a tiny flame.
Kaze ga keshite shimawanai you ni
You have to cup it in both hands
futatsu no te wo kazasu yo.
so that the wind doesn't snuff it out.
Jiyuu tte setsunaku nai desu ka?
Isn't it a painful thing to be free?
Hitori ni nattan da ne.
You're all alone now, aren't you?
Jiyuu tte setsunaku nai desu ka?
Isn't it a painful thing to be free?
Doko made mo.
Utterly and completely.
Hyaku no kotoba yori
There's something I want to tell you
tsutaetai koto ga aru.
that's more than words can say.
Hyaku no kotoba yori
I care for you and you alone
kimi dake wo omotte iru.
more than words can say.
Jiyuu tte setsunaku nai desu ka?
Isn't it a painful thing to be free?
Otona ni nattan da ne.
You've grown up, haven't you?
Jiyuu tte setsunaku nai desu ka?
Isn't it a painful thing to be free?
Doko made mo.
Utterly and completely.
Jiyuu tte setsunaku nai desu ka?
Isn't it a painful thing to be free?
Kimi wa hitori ni nattan da ne.
You're all alone now, aren't you?
Jiyuu tte setsunaku nai desu ka?
Isn't it a painful thing to be free?
Doko made mo.
Utterly and completely.
Me no mae no kimi wa
The "you" standing before me
ima no ima dake no kimi ja nai.
is more than the "you" of only right now.
Deatta ikutsu mo no yorokobi ya
You are living with all the countless joys
kanashimi to issho ni ikiteru.
and sadness you have ever come across.
Preview
If you desire power. . .
enter into this pact
Those with impure hearts
drowning in hatred
The battle against
the mad warriors begins
Episode 2
The Wyvern Divided